Guide to the William A. Speck Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William A. Speck papers
1848-1951
YCGL MSS 20
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
9
(24 boxes)
Collection consists of correspondence, notes and drafts, card files, personal and family papers, documenting the founding of the Speck Collection and William A. Speck's activity as a Goethe collector and interpreter.
Speck, William A. (William Alfred), 1864-1928
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The William A. Speck Papers consist of material brought to Yale by Speck and generated by him while he was curator of the Speck Collection. The papers were left in the library when Speck died, except for a small section of personal papers purchased from a descendant in 1960.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
WILLIAM A. SPECK (1864-1928)
William Alfred Speck, the founder of the William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana, was born in New York City to German immigrants, Otto Speck, a pharmacist, and Natalie Adolphine Haase. He was married twice, to Lillie Day Robinson in 1893 (she died three years later) and to Sara Rennie Speck, the widow of his brother Oscar. His professional training was at the Pharmaceutical College in New York City, and from 1883 until 1912 he worked in the family drug store in Haverstraw, New York. All the while, he was amassing a major Goethe library, and in 1913 he accepted Yale's invitation to come to the university and deposit his collection in the library. He acted as its curator from 1913 until his death in 1928 and as lecturer in the Yale Graduate School beginning in 1916.
A more detailed biography of Speck may be found in the National Cyclopedia of American Biography (vol. 29) and in Goethe's Works with the Exception of Faust: A Catalogue. Edited by Carl F.Schreiber (New Haven, 1940), p. 21-42. Schreiber's account of Speck's early years is based on a text written by Sara R. Speck and preserved among the Speck Collection manuscripts (YCGL MSS 6, folder 657).
History of the William A. Speck Collection of Goetheana
Yale acquired the Speck Collection in 1913 through a set of fortuitous coincidences. Speck's niece, Charlotte Keeney, belonged to the Vassar College Class of 1912. Perhaps at her uncle's suggestion, she took several Goethe courses in college, at least one of them taught by Marian Parker Whitney, a daughter of Yale's distinguished Sanskrit scholar William Dwight Whitney. In February 1912, Charlotte Keeney arranged for Ms. Whitney and a group of Vassar students to visit Uncle Will's Goethe collection, already numbering some 6,000 items, at his home in Haverstraw, New York. Recognizing the importance of the collection and perhaps encouraged by her father (who had studied in Germany and taught German at Yale), Marian Whitney suggested to the Yale University Librarian John Christopher Schwab (Class of 1886 and grandson of the German writer Gustav Schwab) that he might visit the remarkable collection on the Hudson. The German literary scholar Julius Petersen, visiting professor at Yale during the year 1912/13, also saw the collection and arranged for part of it to be exhibited at the University. Hanns Oertel, another native German and dean of the Yale Graduate School, lent his support to the project, as did Alfred Lawrence Ripley, Yale Class of 1878, who had taught German at Yale before becoming a banker and Fellow of the Yale Corporation. Within a year, Yale had negotiated the acquisition of the Speck Collection, bringing William Speck to New Haven as its first curator. These events are documented in the correspondence files of Marian Whitney, John Christopher Schwab, Julius Peterson, Hanns Oertel, Anson Phelps Stokes, and the material filed under Yale University, Office of the Secretary, which includes the drafts of the original contract between Speck and Yale.
Scope and Contents
The William A. Speck Papers document the founding of the Speck Collection and Speck's activities as a Goethe collector and interpreter, both before he came to Yale and during his tenure as curator at the University Library. The collections consists of card files, personal and family papers, correspondence, and notes and drafts for articles and lectures.
Arrangement
The collections is organized into four series: I. Card Files, circa 1914-1927. II. Personal and Family Papers, 1848-1951. III. Correspondence, circa 1893-1928. IV. Notes and Drafts for Articles and Lectures, circa 1870-1927.
Authors, German; German literature -- 18th century; German literature -- 19th century; Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832; Speck, William A. (William Alfred), 1864-1928
- Card Files, circa 1914-1927; Series I; (5 boxes)
  - Card file of the Ehrhardt Faust Collection, arranged by the collector's numbering system, mostly in an elegant German hand, probably the collector's. (paper slips approximately 4x6 inches) (Box 1–2)
  - Early card file of the Speck Collection, in two hands, neither of them WAS's; the earlier cards have prices in code. (5x7 index cards) (Box 3)
  - Cards listing William A. Speck's activities relating to the collection year by year, including publications issued, courses taught, and lectures given. In some cases, student attendance records are present., 1914-1927 (Box 3)
  - Cards headed "special funds," which appear to record individual monetary gifts and what was purchased with each. (Box 3)
  - Card file of donors in kind, listing the donated items. (Box 3)
  - Paper list of the collection in William A. Speck's hand recording 2,021 items. Incomplete? (Box 3)
  - Card file of Speck Collection. This file appears to supplement rather than duplicate the one in Box 3. The cards for manuscripts are in William A. Speck's hand. (3x5 index cards) (Box 4–5)
- Personal and family papers, 1848-1951; Series II; (1 box)
  - Botanical specimens collected by William A. Speck around Haverstraw, NY, 1880s (Box 6)
  - Personal papers and documents, 1848-1897 (Box 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes medical bills, a certificate of introduction from the State Department (1897), a testimonial from the College of Pharmacy, City of New York (1883), and a certificate concerning Otto Speck's apprenticeship at a pharmacy in Germany (1848)
  - William A. Speck, printed obituaries and testimonials (Box 6)
  - Sara R. Speck, letters of condolence to her after William A. Speck's death, 1928 (Box 6)
  - Sara R. Speck, letters to her from Yale librarians Schreiber and Keogh, 1929-1940 (Box 6)
  - Sara R. Speck, letters to her from Alice Raphael, 1929- (Box 6)
  - Sara R. Speck, miscellaneous correspondence, including one letter from her to William A. Speck. (Box 6)
  - Correspondents include William Lyon Phelps and the National Cyclopedia of American Biography (Box 6)
  - Family Papers
    These family papers were found in an envelope marked as follows in the hand of Hedwig S. Dejon, then librarian of the German Literature Collection: "This material concerning Mr. Speck and his family (including some photographs) was sold to YUL [Yale University Library] for a nominal sum by one of the descendants (unidentified) now living in Tennessee. Received 2/23/60 from Accessions Division."
    - Photographs. Included are persons and houses (Box 6)
    - Silhouettes of William A. Speck's grandparents, in oval frames (identified in acknowledgment to Sara R. Speck, 1949) (Box 6)
    - William A. Speck, family letters, 1897-1928 (Box 6)
      File includes letters from his nephew William, 1907 March 16; two letters to his sister Augusta, 1897 and n.y; two letters to Sara R. Speck, 1928 and n.y.
    - Sara R. Speck, correspondence from Yale librarians Schreiber and Keogh, 1930-1949 (Box 6)
    - Sara R. Speck, family letters: from and about her son Oscar O. Speck and his wife Eleanor H. Speck; "Bill," possibly her son William; and "Annie," possibly William's second wife, 1936-1951 (Box 6)
    - Sara R. Speck, miscellaneous letters to her. Correspondents include Ethel Rowe, Anne Pratt, Ellen Battell Stoeckel, Alice Raphael, and a lawyer., 1928-1951 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, circa 1893-1928; Series III; (13 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Files are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  This series contains a mixture of business, academic, and institutional correspondence, with a few letters from old friends who have nothing to do with Yale or Goethe but often relate to Speck's other interests, such as botany and geology. The correspondence sometimes gives brief glimpses into his politics, especially the letters from Oswald Garrison Villard.
  Orders, invoices, offers, and letters from antiquarian dealers in Germany, England, France, the United States, Switzerland, the Netherlands, and Japan document the growth of the Speck Collection from its inception in the late 1880s until Speck's death in 1928. The earliest evidence of his collecting is in the file for E. Steiger & Co. in New York City, with whom William Speck placed a subscription to the Weimar Edition of Goethe's works in 1887. Many of the earliest invoices in the collection are for coins and medals, suggesting that portraits and likenesses of Goethe were among Speck's earliest collecting interests. The most extensive dealer files are Maggs Brothers in London, Joseph Baer in Berlin, and Leo Liepmannsohn in Leipzig. These files, along with many shorter files of correspondence with other dealers, bridge the private and Yale years of Speck's collecting activity.
  The correspondence also documents acquisitions from private individuals, such as the extensive negotiations to acquire a group of Goethe-related autographs from the Chicago collector Oliver R. Barrett in exchange for U.S. Presidential letters. A similarly wide-ranging correspondence preceded the purchase of the manuscript of Bayard Taylor's Faust translation. Private collections were also purchased in Germany during Speck's Yale years, among them the 6,000 pieces of Faustiana gathered by G. W. Ehrhardt (acquired in 1922) and 4,000 prints, maps, and ephemera amassed by Karl Berg and purchased from his widow Anna in 1928. The Ehrhardt purchase is an example of the way many Germans were forced to sell their collections because of the severe inflation in Germany after the First World War. Speck's correspondence files of the 1920s are, in fact, full of letters from private individuals offering Goethe-related possessions, in the hope of obtaining small amounts of hard cash in dollars. While Speck took advantage of this situation to augment the collection, it is also clear that he rescued numerous people in extremely difficult circumstances.
  In developing the Goethe collection at Yale, Speck had solid support from several faculty members and officers of the University. Among the notable correspondence files in this regard are the letters from Professor Gustav Gruener of the German Department; from Carl F. Schreiber, who was to succeed Speck as curator of the collection; from Anson Phelps Stokes, Secretary of the University; from Hanns Oertel, Dean of the Graduate School; from John Christopher Schwab, University Librarian; and from William Lyon Phelps, perhaps Yale's most illustrious professor of English at the time. Phelps often wrote in German, and once signed himself "Wilhelm Löwe Phelps."
  Special mention should be made of the extensive file of letters from Alice Pearl Raphael, whose translation of Goethe's Faust I was published in New York by J. Cape and H. Smith in 1930. Alice Raphael adopted Speck as her principal advisor as she worked on the translation, often traveling to New Haven for consultations. After Speck's death, she continued to write to Sara R. Speck and to Carl F. Schreiber. Related letters are to be found in the Wilson Follett file. Alice Raphael's papers are part of the Yale Collection of German Literature. (In the Speck correspondence, Alice Raphael's letters are filed under her married name, Eckstein.)
  Speck's interest in English translations of Goethe has, in fact, given enduring shape to the Speck Collection, with its particular strength in the reception of Goethe's works in Great Britain and the United States. His research on the English novelist, traveler, and linguist George Henry Borrow, for instance, threads through both the correspondence and the essay series of the papers and led to an exchange of letters with the notorious forger Thomas Wise, who made a gift to the collection of several Borrow manuscripts. George Borrow translated Ferdinand Maximilian Klinger's 1791 novel Fausts Leben, Thaten und Höllenfahrt, and manuscripts of Borrow's English renderings of scenes from Goethe's Faust are present in the Speck Collection (YCGL MSS 6, folders 225-27).
  - A general (includes James R. Angell, Yale president, 2 letters, 1922) (Box 7)
  - Ackermann, Theodor (book dealer, Munich) (Box 7)
  - Addresses and calling cards, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - American Art Association, The American Art Galleries, Inc.(dealer, NYC) (Box 7)
  - Asakawa, Kan-ichi (clipping) (Box 7)
  - B general (Box 7)
  - Baer, Joseph (book dealer, Frankfurt a.M.), 1893-1928 (Box 7)
  - Bangs, Archie R. (Yale PhD, 1928, taught at Trinity College in Hartford) (Box 7)
  - Barrett, Oliver R. (collector, Chicago) (Box 7)
  - Baumgärtel, Otto (Collective Exhibition of the German Book Trade) (Box 8)
  - Beall, Edgar C. (phrenologist; collector with Bayard Taylor interests) (Box 8)
  - Behrend, Fritz (Faust collector, Berlin) (Box 8)
  - Belwe, Max (offers of 1480 Bible) (Box 8)
  - Berg, Anna (Box 8)
    Concerning the purchase of her late husband's collection of prints and maps in 1928. Related material can be found in YCGL MSS 8, folder 659 (Speck's account of the Berg Collection); and in YCGL administrative files
  - Berlin Photographic Company (NYC) (Box 8)
  - Bewer, Julius A. (Box 8)
    Regarding the sale of Goethe letters on behalf of Professor Karl Budde, whose letters are also filed here
  - Bloch, Richard (collector: medals, Faust) (Box 8)
  - Bochum (Goethe Week there in 1928) (Box 8)
  - Bonaventure, E. F. Inc. (art dealer, NYC) (Box 8)
  - Boucke, Ewald A. (U. of Michigan; Goethe scholar) (Box 8)
  - Brandegee, Emily (Byron's rose) (Box 8)
  - Breslauer, Martin (book dealer, Berlin) (Box 8)
  - Briggs, Walter B. (Harvard College Library) (Box 8)
  - Brick Row Book Shop (NYC) (Box 8)
  - Brigham, Clarence S. (librarian, American Antiquarian Society) (Box 8)
  - Brooke, C. F. Tucker (Yale English Department, Shakespeare scholar) (Box 8)
  - Brown, Carlton (Modern Language Association, Chaucer scholar) (Box 8)
  - Bruderhausen, A. (book dealer, NYC) (Box 8)
  - Budde, Karl. See Bewer, Julius (Box 8)
  - C general (including Bruno Cassirer) (Box 8)
  - Cadmus Book Shop (NYC) (Box 8)
  - Cahn, Adolph E. (dealer in medals, Frankfurt) (Box 8)
  - Campbell, T. M. (German Dept., Wesleyan University) (Box 8)
  - Canby, Henry Seidel (manuscript of Bayard Taylor's Faust translation) (Box 8)
  - Carey, Frederic and Margaret (Trippel bust) (Box 8)
  - Carpenter, Fred Donald (Yale PhD 1918, taught at U. of Vermont) (Box 8)
  - Carus, Paul (Open Court Publishing Company) (Box 8)
  - Chaney, Ann Elizabeth (Lake Erie College) (Box 8)
  - Church, Howard Wadsworth (Yale 1904, PhD 1913, professor; with studio photograph) (Box 8)
  - Clark, John Mowbray (sculptor) (Box 8)
  - Claudy, C. H. (son of Frank Claudy, Faust translator) (Box 8)
  - Cohen, Friedrich (book dealer, Bonn) (Box 9)
  - Connecticut Library Association (with draft of Speck's lectured in Waterbury in Feb. 1916) (Box 9)
  - Cook, Albert Stanburrough (Yale English Department) (Box 9)
  - Cooper, W. A. ( German Dept., Stanford University) (Box 9)
  - Croke, William J. D. (Box 9)
  - Cross, Wilbur L. (at that time, Professor of English at Yale and dean of the Graduate School) (Box 9)
  - Curts, Paul Holroyd (German Dept., Wesleyan Unversity) (Box 9)
  - D general (Box 9)
  - Day, George Parmly (Box 9)
  - Davies, James (University of Minnesota) (Box 9)
  - Dartmouth College (correspondence with Warren Austin Adams) (Box 9)
  - Danielson, Henry (book dealer, London) (Box 9)
  - Deutsche Gesellschaft der Stadt New Haven (Box 9)
  - Dice, J. Howard (University of Pittsburgh Library) (Box 9)
  - Dobell, P. J. & A. E. (book dealers, London) (Box 9)
  - E general (Box 9)
  - Eckstein, Alice Raphael (also known as Alice Pearl Raphael, Faust translator). (Box 9)
    Related material in Alice Pearl Raphael papers, Uncat Zg MS 22; in the Carl Schreiber papers, Uncat Zg MS 20 and in the Speck Collection. Books classed in Speck Tr are from her collection
  - Ettinghausen, Maurice L. (Maggs Bros., Napoleon's copy of Werther ) (Box 9)
  - F general (Box 10)
  - Farr, Hollon A. (Yale College faculty) (Box 10)
  - Fife, Robert Herndon (Columbia and Wesleyan) (Box 10)
  - Fischerauer, Friedrich (Austrian Consul General, concerns Franz Aschoner) (Box 10)
  - Fittbogen, Gottfried (German scholar) (Box 10)
  - Fock, Gustav (book dealer, Leipzig; agent in purchase of Ehrhardt Faust collection) (Box 10)
  - Follett, Wilson (Yale University Press; concerns Alice Raphael's Faust translation) (Box 10)
  - Fleischer, Fritz (artist; Yale purchased his painting Mehr Licht; see also Francke, Otto) (Box 10)
  - Francke, Kuno (Harvard University) (Box 10)
  - Francke, Otto (concerns Fritz Fleischer portrait of Goethe, Mehr Licht ) (Box 10)
  - Frossard, Edward (dealer in coins and medals, NYC) (Box 10)
  - G general (Box 10)
  - Gardner, F. L. (book dealer, London) (Box 10)
  - Gerring, Rudolf (book dealer, Basel) (Box 10)
  - George, C. E. (sale of books) (Box 10)
  - Germanic Review (Box 10)
  - Glaser, Edward L (donor, Chicago) (Box 10)
  - Godard, Georg S. (Connecticut State Library) (Box 10)
  - Goethe Gesellschaft, Weimar (Box 10)
  - Goethe- und Schiller-Archiv, Weimar (Box 10)
  - Goodspeed's Book Shop (Boston) (Box 10)
  - Gottschalk, Paul (book and autograph dealer, Berlin) (Box 10)
  - Gougy, Lucien (book dealer, Paris) (Box 10)
  - Gräf, Hans Gerhard (Goethe scholar, poet, Weimar) (Box 10)
  - Graham, Alexander S. (purchase of a drawing) (Box 11)
  - Grant, John (book dealer, Edinburgh) (Box 11)
  - Graupe, Paul (book dealer, Berlin) (Box 11)
  - Gray, Milton (book dealer, West Norwood, NJ) (Box 11)
  - Grolier Club (Byron exhibition, 1924) (Box 11)
  - Gruener, Gustav (Yale 1884, PhD 1896, Yale German Dept. faculty. His papers are at Manuscripts & Archives, SML) (Box 11)
  - H general (Box 11)
  - Hadley, Arthur (Yale president) (Box 11)
  - Hamburger, Leo (dealer in coins, Frankfurt a.M.) (Box 11)
  - Harrassowitz, Otto (book dealer, Leipzig) (Box 11)
  - Hatfield, James Taft (Northwestern University) (Box 11)
  - Hauhart, William F. (University of Michigan) (Box 11)
  - Hecker, Max (professor, Weimar) (Box 11)
  - Hector, E. (book dealer, Birmingham) (Box 11)
  - Heise, John (autograph dealer, Syracuse, NY) (Box 11)
  - Hellersberg (book dealer, Charlottenburg) (Box 11)
  - Hensel, Bruckmann & Lorbacher, Inc, (custom brokers, NYC) (Box 11)
  - Hess, Adolf, Nachf. (dealer in coins, Frankfurt a.M.) (Box 11)
  - Heuer, Otto (Freies deutsches Hochstift; related material filed under Hochstift) (Box 11)
  - Hiersemann, Karl W. (book dealer, Leipzig; file goes back to 1891, among earliest material in the collection) (Box 11)
  - Hinrichs, Frederic W. (donor of Goethe portrait by Julius Zuber) (Box 11)
  - Hinsdale, Ellen C. (Mount Holyoke College) (Box 11)
  - Hochstift, Freies deutsches (see also Otto Heuer) (Box 12)
  - Höfer, Conrad (sale of a Höllenzwang manuscript by Kippenberg) (Box 12)
  - Hohlfeld, A. R. (Alexander Rudolf) (University of Wisconsin) (Box 12)
  - Houben, H. H. (scholar; offers to sell Eckermann papers) (Box 12)
  - Howes, C. (book dealer, Hastings) (Box 12)
  - Hünich, Fritz Adolf (Insel Verlag) (Box 12)
  - I-J general (Box 12)
  - International Book Review (Box 12)
  - K general (Box 12)
  - Kartzke, Georg (Amerika-Institut, Berlin; acted as agent for Speck, especially in purchase of the Ehrhardt Faust collection) (Box 12)
  - Kasten, Hans (collector, Bremen) (Box 12)
  - Kellermann, Fritz (University of Kansas) (Box 12)
  - Kemp, James Furman (geologist) (Box 12)
  - Keogh, Andrew (Yale University Librarian) (Box 12)
  - Kiliani, Lilian (daughter of Bayard Taylor) (Box 12)
    With the letters is her translation of Auguste Mariette's "Outline History of Egypt," autograph manuscript, 149 numbered leaves.
  - Kippenberg, Anton (Insel Verlag) (Box 13)
  - Kintzel O. R. (book dealer, Hartford) (Box 13)
  - Klenze, Camillo von (City College) (Box 13)
  - Knortz, Karl (folklorist) (Box 13)
  - Krumpelmann, John T. (scholar with interest in Bayard Taylor) (Box 13)
  - Kuhn, Grete (offers lock of Goethe's hair; with hair sample, not Goethe's) (Box 13)
  - Kurrelmeyer, William (Johns Hopkins) (Box 13)
  - L general (Box 13)
  - Ladd, Benjamin Franklin (Yale graduate student) (Box 13)
  - Landau, Toni, Photographic Co. (Box 13)
  - Libbie, C. F. & Co. (auction house, Boston) (Box 13)
  - Liepmannssohn, Leo (book dealer, Berlin) (Box 13)
  - Long, Orie William (Williams College) (Box 13)
  - Loughridge, Charles (mining executive, donor) (Box 13)
  - Luyster, S. B. (book dealer, NYC; invoices going back to 1890) (Box 13)
  - M general (Box 14)
  - Mackall, Leonard L. (bibliophile, collector, writer) (Box 14)
    Correspondence continues with Carl Schreiber after Speck's death. There is a group of Mackall's papers at Manuscripts & Archives and correspondence in the Harvey Cushing Papers at the Medical Library
  - Mackowsky, Hans (Nationalgalerie, Berlin; Rauch bust) (Box 14)
  - Madigan, Thomas F. (autograph dealer, NYC) (Box 14)
  - Maggs Bros. (book dealer, London), 1906-1927; 2 (Box 15)
  - Malkan, Henry (book dealer, NYC) (Box 15)
  - Marc, Hedwig (sale of autographs) (Box 15)
  - Markham, L. O. (Box 15)
    Concerns Speck's plan to create a natural history museum in a school near Haverstraw, 1913.
  - Maruzen Company (book dealer, Kyoto) (Box 15)
  - Mensel, Ernst Heinrich (Smith College) (Box 15)
  - Merwin Sales Company (book, autograph, coin dealer, NYC) (Box 15)
  - Meyer, Friedrich, Buchhandlung (Leipzig) (Box 15)
  - Muel, Charles (book dealer, London) (Box 15)
  - Mincieux, C. A. (book dealer, Geneva) (Box 15)
  - Modern Language Association (programs) (Box 15)
  - Monahan, James (attorney; sale of Bayard Taylor's Faust manuscript) (Box 15)
  - Monrad, Anna M. (Yale University Library cataloguer) (Box 15)
  - Morford, Eben P. (acquisition of Braille books) (Box 15)
  - Morgan, Alice W. (facsimile Schiller letter) (Box 15)
  - Morgan, Bayard Quincy (University of Wisconsin) (Box 15)
  - N general (Box 16)
  - Nettleton, George H. (Yale English Dept. faculty) (Box 16)
  - Neumann Bros. (bookbinders, NYC) (Box 16)
  - New England Modern Language Association (Box 16)
  - Nijhoff, Martinus (book dealer, The Hague) (Box 16)
  - North, Ernest Dressel (book dealer, NYC) (Box 16)
  - O general (Box 16)
  - O'Connell, Richard D. (Yale 1923) (Box 16)
  - O'Donnell, George H. F. (Yale PhD, 1921) (Box 16)
  - Oertel, Hanns (dean, Yale Graduate School) (Box 16)
  - Oettingen, Wolfgang (director, Goethe Museum, Weimar) (Box 16)
  - Olmstead, Anna E. (Vassar College) (Box 16)
  - Ormes, Ferguson R. (Yale 1913) (Box 16)
  - P general (including Frederick A. Pottel and Eduard Prokosch) (Box 16)
  - Palmer, Arthur Hubbell (Yale German Department faculty) (Box 16)
  - Penny, George B. (Rochester Institute of Musical Art, old friend) (Box 16)
  - Petersen, Julius (visiting professor at Yale when Speck Collection was acquired) (Box 16)
  - Phelps, William Lyon (Yale English Department faculty) (Box 16)
  - Picard, Auguste (book dealer, Paris) (Box 16)
  - Pleadwell, F. L. (U. S. Navy; has to do with Byron's rose) (Box 16)
  - Plée, M. (book dealer, Paris) (Box 16)
  - Presbyterian Church, Stamford, NY (lecture, January 1921) (Box 16)
  - Press clipping agencies (Box 16)
  - Princeton University Library (Box 16)